Hi, Conf42.
My name is Oleksandr Kryuchenko.
I'm Staff as Dad and team
lead in cybersecurity space.
Today, I wanna talk about CloudCode
security, about settings.json,
and certain permissions that we can set
in order to make our setup more reliable.
Yeah, without further ado,
let's move to the slide deck.
one question that we need to answer, yeah,
when AI, agents ignores the deny list.
let's try to find out together, and I
will show you my setup that is working
for my project, and hopefully it will
help to secure, your projects as well.
So that's a regular settings.json
policy, that gets created on a
first installation of CloudCode,
and I'm more than sure all
of you is familiar with this.
But there are multiple
ways how you can set it up.
At this very moment, what
we have certain guardrails.
Yeah, we preventing shell deletions,
we preventing outbound, network
connection, wr curl, and we don't want
our, our AI agent to read the secrets.
pretty good, reasonable setup,
but it could be improved.
Let's see how.
So at this very moment, we, with
single REM command, we actually
block it, multiple, invocation and
multiple instances of that command.
we, actually, prevented,
leading assignment.
We preventing, the timeout
as a wrapper on top.
Very, common technique
in penetration testing.
Also, we are, we're smart enough to
see that, compound commands can be
utilized as well and we block those.
However, if this enough,
let's test it out.
Let's move to the terminal, and
let's try to see, actually how
this will work In action, yeah.
So I will try to test
right now our deny list.
And as we can see, I executed 57
different commands, and tried to see
if I will get deny or allowed results.
So when we just utilized the plain
dot at the end, we got denied.
Beautiful, because of our policy.
Then we tried, So this through the
cat command and it's also got blocked.
But then, we tried the
absolute path, let's say.
Yeah, we tried absolute path to the
cat command and then we bypassed our,
policy that was secure, at first glance.
Not a secret, not, not
a surprise, obviously.
And look at this, there are multiple
ways how we can get creative and
AI is very creative, trust me, how
we can actually read our secrets.
So we can use the, program subprocess.
Yeah, we can use a, we can use
a direct grep command actually,
without even knowing the file name,
but knowing the variable key, we
can read the secret right away.
And yep, so that's complete disaster
from a security perspective.
the question is, can
we, make it more secure?
And the simple answer, yes, but it
requires certain settings on your end
and it's pretty easy to set it up.
However, we need to
talk about some details.
So let's try to understand
why it's happening, yeah.
Because, you just try to block one
spelling of the certain command, but
the, program has ultimate numbers
of spelling and it's actually hard
to predict all possible instances.
And if you just create thousand
lines deny policy, you still might
gonna miss a few of those, rules that
will actually expose your secrets.
So what to do?
what to do, it's actually to set up the
pre-tool hook that will help you, not
guess, but actually try to understand
the intent and prevent bad things from
happening on the tool level before your
input is traveling to the agent itself.
Let's see how this work on practice.
First of all, I wanna show you
on the updated policy that will
already have a, a hook set up.
So hook will point us
to the, our guard file.
It's regular .sh
script, but you can set any extension.
And this, denyguard.sh
has a set of rules that are useful for
my project and I just wanna highlight
one more time that it's important
for you to set your project and your
guardrails in a way that's required
for your system and architecture.
that's, this tool will get invoked
before each bash tool invocation.
Yeah, so it's acting, right before
and can block something which is
great and, in combination with
other tools and technologies, it
can generate pretty good results.
Yeah I just wanna show you the
terminal how it looks like.
Yeah, so this is our,
updated settings.json.
Here we have our pre-tool hook.
it lives in a denyguard.sh.
The, the core logic lives there,
and it gets invoked before,
before each call of your agent.
Let's go back to the
presentation and let's see.
Ideally, we wanna make sure that even
if someone is calling the, tool with
absolute path, it still gets blocked.
And as we, as we've seen before, our,
deny list actually allowed this command.
It also allowed subprocess to open it,
either Python subprocess or Node.js
subprocess.
Doesn't matter.
Yeah, there are multiple ways how we
can bypass it, our previous setup.
So right now, let's try to actually
execute our test against new policy.
So this is our updated policy,
and let's try to, run our test for
this updated policy and let's see.
All right, so it's 57 commands.
They're trying to break, not to
break in your system, but they try
to read your, secrets, which is
actually prerequisite into intrusion.
what we see here, so let's start from
this absolute path, something that
we s- spoke before that got denied.
That got denied because we have a pre-tool
hook that's actually trying to read
intent and to understand intent before,
and not just blindly match, the string.
Yeah, which is great.
And as we can see, everything that we
wanted to deny here was denied, and it's
even denied some truncate commands, and
it's denied, commands on a program level.
Yeah, it's actually very good.
what else I wanna tell that we
intentionally left some useful commands
for development because we didn't
wanna block npm test, git status,
and we wa- also wanna be able to run
certain configuration file with Python,
depending on your project needs again.
Yeah, so let's go back to
the slide deck and let's talk
about details of this setup.
So we don't wanna, we don't wanna match.
Yeah, as I said, we, you
cannot predict every string.
What we wanna do, one of the technique,
there are multiples, but what we
can do, we can normalize the input.
And we were doing this for decades
on the back-end side, and why not?
we can continue do this with AI as well.
So we are on normalizing our string.
We can strip absolute path, and then
we will see the core intent, and
we can understand this core intent
and either block it or allow it.
As simple as that.
So by the way, on your local, machine,
you at least ca- have a chance to observe
what's going on or maybe if you're
not working in the after mode, you
can approve certain commands manually.
However, when execution is happening on
CI/CD, there is no one who can, sit and
control this execution and, maybe it
will be Friday evening and, no one will
check their a-alarm emails and, only on
Monday someone will find out that it was
a breach or an exi- an accident, yeah.
So I tried to run same testing on
CI/CD and our, regular settings.json
without hook got crashed right away,
and we exposed multiple secrets.
However, our hook was able to,
block 56 instances, of, read
command for a certain secrets.
Yeah, which is great.
So let's move forward.
right now I wanna talk about how to
actually enforce this because, you
probably have reasonable questions
regarding, okay, settings.json
lives on the edge on a user level, so each
user can, just go ahead and remove that
hook, or intentionally or unintentionally.
So m- here it's important to understand
there are three levels of settings
in a cloud code that, one can use.
first one, it's the lowest level,
it's your, project setting, which
is lives inside your directory, and,
do not have those boundaries, yeah.
The second level, it's, user level, yeah.
So it's inside your .cloud
directory.
There are settings.json
that will be invoked for any project
that you will create on y- on the
edge, on your machine, yeah, let's say.
and those policies, they are not cascade.
They actually connects together and
deny from any policy, always wins.
Let's say if you have your user
level policy that allow, read .env,
but your project level policy actually
denies it, even the project level,
policy it's, has a lower precedence, it
will still, deny that, which is great.
However, going back to the
first question, how to make sure
that no one can overwrite it.
For that, there is a
managed settings.json,
policy that can be pushed to the
endpoint, to the, machine, of
certain, individual from org level.
Yeah.
And, those policies, they
are, in a protected path.
They not-- they cannot be overwritten
by the regular user, with, a regular
level of permissions, and they
can be updated, centralized and
set in a way that will satisfy,
security needs of your organization.
So you can add that, pre-tool
hook over there, certain deny
rules and anything that will
help, you with security framework.
So There are three
layers obviously on that.
So the-- And it's nice
to utilize all of them.
I would say it's, never, s-
enough, in terms of security.
The, the more controls
you have, the better.
Obviously, we don't wanna over-engineer
things, but this is just a common sense.
deny list.
The deny list, something
that we discussed.
It's efficient to the certain extent.
It has certain limitations.
Then, custom pre-tool hook
that will help, bad things from
happening, before invocation.
Yeah.
And it will try to match intent, yeah,
not to match blindly, certain strings.
And, obviously, this needs to be
com- combined with a managed policy
to make sure that it's immutable,
those settings are immutable, and we
even can force developers to utilize
sandbox environment, by default.
And again, the level of,
security is on you to decide.
You also wouldn't wanna compromise
ability, for, our team to be
efficient, but we don't wanna
compromise security either.
with that being said, please make
sure to look into your settings.json,
work with your policies.
let me know if you have any questions,
and I would be happy to help you.
Thank you for your time, and it
was pleasure speaking on K0nne42.
Thank you, Mark